在梦里 我就是她
GIBBS: I had a dream that I was her.
我被困住了
I was trapped.
我无法逃离
I could not get out.
但我仍相信会有人来救我
Yet I believed there would be a savior.
直到最后 我仍然坚信着
To the very end, I believed.
但有的时候拯救者从未出现
But sometimes a savior never comes.
♪
Gibbs小队
Team Gibbs!
你们都
Are! You!
准备好了吗
Ready! Ha!
早上好呀 然后
Happy morning, and...
随机日快乐
Happy Random Day.
多谢你啦 为啥送我礼物啊
Oh. Thank you. What is this for?
与其在大家的生日或者圣诞送礼
Oh. Instead of buying for people on Christmas or birthdays,
我选择在一年里随机的一天赠送礼物
I choose one random date each year to give gifts.
但是 为什么呢
Uh... why?
这么做会让你感到自己更特别
What makes you feel more special,
在意料之中的时间收到礼物 跟在某个周二
getting anotherpresent
when you're already rakin' 'em in,
忽然收到一份意外的礼物相比 哪个更有吸引力呢
or getting one...
on a random Tuesday?[McGee gasps]
我的Q键 你在哪儿找到的啊
My "Q" key! Where'd you find this?
-我一直在找这玩意儿 -为了能让你的X28复古打字机变完整 我记得呢
I've been looking for this... For your vintage
X28 Ryson typewriter. Yeah, I know.
之前你提过
You mentioned it in passing.
是啊
McGEE: Yeah.
这不可能
No... way!
我一直想要一条不厚也不薄的围巾
I've been wanting a scarf
that's not too thick and not too thin.
嘿嘿 我记得呢 你之前也说过
Yeah, I know. You mentioned it in passing.
我迫不及待想看看我之前说过什么了
Ooh, I can't wait to see what I mentioned.
这是啥
What is this?
是个罐子呀
It's a jar.
随机日快乐 大家伙儿
Happy Random Day, everybody!
[chuckles]
她送了你一个拳击袋吗
You got a punching bag?
对啊 我在这2018拳馆特制的拳击袋上挥洒的拳头
Yeah, those punches I landed at the Studio-Art Brawl of 2018
让我兴奋不已
really got my juices flowing.
我之前说过我想要一个这样的拳击袋
I mentioned in passing I wanted to get one...KASIE: Yeah.
是啊
虽然是二手的 但是依然很迷人
It's secondhand, but it's a beauty.
你知道吗 我想我会把拳击袋带回家的
You know, I think I might take it home.
我本来想把这个放在停尸间的
I was gonna, uh, leave it down in Autopsy,
但你能想象Gibbs瞪我的眼神吗
but can you imagine the glare I would have gotten from Gibbs?
他现在就在瞪着你呢
Oh, you're getting a pretty good one right now.
Gibbs 真是不赶巧
Gibbs. What terrible timing.
我说我的时间不赶巧 不是你的哈
I mean me, my timing, not yours.
我赶紧把这玩意挪开
Uh, let me move this for you.
收拾东西
Grab your gear!
在海军基地有案子了
We have a situation on base.
Gibbs 随机日快乐
Uh, hey, Gibbs. Happy Random Day.
我替你把一大块木头挂在我车顶上了
I have a hunk of a tree strapped to the top of my car for you.
我在路边找到的它
I found it by the side of the road,
我想你可以尽情发挥你的木工手艺
and I thought you could just woodwork
the crap out of it.
-他的背影看起来非常激动 -是吗 你这么想的吗
JIMMY: Well, the back of him
looked really excited.You think?
是呀
Oh, yeah, yeah.
我不清楚 你希望我说什么呢
I don't know. What do you want me to say?
我告诉你 我从未见过她
I'm telling you, I have never seen her before.All right,
好吧 伙计 但是你得冷静下来
we're gonna need you to calm down.Are you gonna help or not?
你要来帮忙吗 还是就在这儿傻站着
请你在这等一下
Just wait here.
那个大兵说他发现一个小女孩躲在他的储藏室里
The guy says
he found a young girl hiding in his storage unit.
小女孩不肯出来
She won't come out.He said
他说小女孩被他吓着了 然后躲在了那些盒子后面
she's terrified of him. She's hiding
behind some boxes in there.
好吧 请确保他告诉了我们全部的信息
All right. Just make sure
he's giving us the whole story, huh?
Bishop 跟我来
Bishop, with me.
你好呀
Hey there.
我是特别探员Gibbs
My name is Special Agent Gibbs.
你知道你爸爸妈妈在哪儿吗
Do you know where your parents are?
她一直盯着你看
[quietly]: She keeps looking at you.
你来试试看
Give it a try.
好的
[quietly]: Okay.
嘿
Hey.
我是Ellie
I'm Ellie.
你叫什么呀
What's your name?
Lily
Lily.
Lily是吗
Lily, huh?
这可真是个好名字
That's a really good name.
Lily你住在哪儿呀
Hey, where do you live, Lily?
住在一个地下室
In the basement.
附近公寓的地下室吗
In an apartment around here?
嘿
Hey.
你冷吗
You cold?
你想不想穿我的大衣
Do you want to wear my coat?
大衣是什么
What's that?
哦
Oh.
这是件夹克
It's a jacket, 'cause...
因为如果不穿着它出去就太冷了啊
it...
is way too cold
to go outside without it.
我从不出门
I don't go outside.
Lily
Hey, Lily...
你是一直住在那个地下室吗
the basement where you live,
这是你第一次出地下室吗
is this your first time outside of it?
他把门锁上了
He locks the door.
妈妈试图打开门
Mommy tries to open it...
但是他每次都把门锁死
but he always locks it.
你妈妈也在地下室住是吗
Your mom was in the basement, too?
她现在还住在地下室
[voice breaks]: She's still there.
哪儿的地下室 Lily
Where, Lily?
你知道我们怎么回你家去找你妈妈吗
Do you know how to get back to where your mom is?
不知道
[crying]: No.
好的
[whispers]: Okay.
[sighs]
医生说Lily重度营养不良
Doctor says she's undernourished
而且极易感染疾病
and highly susceptible to illness.Spend your whole life
任何一个人在地下室呆一辈子 都得没免疫力
locked in one room, you have no immunity.
医生说她得在医院再呆几天
Mm. They're gonna keep her for a few more days,
养好她的身体 再多进行几项检查
build her strength, run some more tests.
她说过任何有关她妈妈位置的线索吗
She say anything else about where her mom is?
没有 她现在状况越来越差
SLOANE: No. She's regressing by the minute.
随着她对陌生而又巨大的世界感到越来越不可思议
The more overwhelmed she becomes by this huge, foreign world,
她对地下室的记忆就越少
the more she retreats-- plus,
还有 那些医生原以为
what the doctors originally thought
是虫噬的印记其实是烫伤
were bug bites on her arms and legs were actually burns.
[exhales]
我可以试试看再和她谈谈
I, uh, I could try to talk to her again.
这主意不错
That's not a bad idea.
Lily最相信的就是她妈妈 但是她妈妈不在
Lily's without the one person in the world she trusts.
-是啊 她母亲 -对
Yeah. Her mother.Yes.
而且她天生相信女性
And she defaults to trusting women
因为男性在对她施虐
because of what she suffered at the hands of a man.
你认为你能撬开她的嘴吗
You think that you can get her to talk?
Gibbs
Gibbs...
我已经和她产生了友好的联系
I already made a connection with her.Bishop,
Bishop 小女孩需要我们出外勤
that girl needs us in the field.
去外面寻找蛛丝马迹 从而拯救她妈妈 我们赶紧吧
Chase down every lead we can. We find her mom. Come on.
好吧
Okay.
进展 说吧
Update. Let's go.
来了来了
KASIE: Incoming.
我们对比到了一条DNA 朋友们
We got ourselves a DNA hit, people.
我在国防部数据库里找到了
I found a familial match to Lily
一个和Lily有亲缘关系的人
in the DoD database.
-你找到了Lily的妈妈吗 -是的
You ID'd Lily's mother?Yep.
她是海军的候补水兵
She is Navy Seaman Recruit
Morgan Burke
Morgan Burke.
我记得她
McGEE: I remember her.
她被报告失踪 得有 八年了吧
She was reported missing, what, eight years ago?
十年
Ten.
老大
Boss?
我去透透气
Getting some air.
Gibbs去透气
Gibbs gets air?
我找到NCIS的调查记录了 18岁的
I've got the NCIS Report of Investigation. "18-year-old
Morgan Burke被她妈妈报告失踪
"Morgan Burke was reported missing by her mother.
Morgan已经完成了海军的宣誓
"Morgan had been sworn into the Navy
-但是从来没有去报到 -对的
but never reported for duty."McGEE: That's right.
她还没有真正开始服役
She hadn't really started her service yet,
所以NCIS把案子移交到了警长办公室
so NCIS handed the case over to the sheriff's office.
我找到了那时候的一些新闻文章
I pulled up some news articles from back then.
据她妈妈讲 Morgan失踪的时候
According to her mother, Morgan was pregnant at the time
-已经怀孕了 -是的 然后他们就
of her disappearance.McGEE: Yeah, and then they
在车里发现了她的尸体 是吧
found her body in the car, right?
她是因为车掉下了悬崖而死的
Well, her car had gone off a cliff,
据说她的遗体
killing her.KASIE: It says her remains
已经烧焦了
were charred.
仅有的那一点DNA证据也被污染了
What little DNA they pulled was contaminated.
-他们以自杀结案的 -是 但是如果Morgan
They ruled it a suicide.Yeah, but if Morgan
还活着 那在车里的
is still alive, that's someone else's remains
就是别人的遗体了
who were in that car.
嗯 而Morgan 她在怀孕的时候被绑架了
Well, and Morgan, she was abducted when she was pregnant,
然后她在被囚禁的时候生下了Lily
and she had Lily in captivity...
她一定是从那时候开始就被关在地下室里了
She must have been held prisoner in that basement ever since.
十年了 报告上说
Ten years. The report says there's
-在附属物里还有后续的文件 -为什么在
a continued file at the annex.Why do we have
移交了案子之后我们还有后续文件
the continued file when we handed over the case?
我不知道 但我会查的
I don't know. But I'll check it out.
-我来帮忙 -要知道
I'll help.You know,
Lily不可能从地下室
Lily couldn't have gotten that far
跑那么远 我会在方圆五英里内
from the basement on foot, so I'm gonna start
搜索Morgan
the search grid for Morgan at a five-mile radius.
我是
MAN: My name is
Paul Atwood警探
Detective Paul Atwood.
我主管了十年前
I headed up the investigation
Morgan Burke失踪案的调查
into Morgan Burke's disappearance ten years ago.
哟 Gibbs 快进来
Why, Gibbs. Come on in.
我们的小队当初把这个案子认定为自杀
I was on a team that ruled this a suicide at that time,
我会为这个严重错误负全责
and I take full responsibility for that grave error.
我会找到Morgan
I will find Morgan,
我会把她带回家
and I will bring her home.
-别说 -他们只需要做的一件事
Don't say it.One thing they had to do:
别牵扯上媒体
keep it out of the press.
我必须得告诉他们进展 Gibbs
I had to update them, Gibbs.
你想怎么说都行
You can spin this any way you want,
但这是布林县警长的调查
but it was a Breen County Sheriff's investigation.
他们为了在公众面前挽回面子就把这事儿弄到电视上
They went public with it to try to save face on TV.
我不知道他们
I can't begin to figure out
脑子里都在想什么 Gibbs
what went on in their heads, Gibbs.
我们压根就不应该把案子移交出去
We never should have handed this case off.
瞧瞧你 现在提起当年了
Well, look at you. Bringing up ten years ago?
-是的 -那可真是新鲜事儿
Yes, I am.Well, that's a new one.
通常往事会追在你屁股后头
Usually the past is nipping at your ass,
而你恨不得尽全力朝另一边跑
and you're running full steam ahead the other way.Morgan Burke
Morgan Burke是海军 那个案子本来应该是咱们的
was Navy-- that case should have been ours.
她一天都没有去服役
She hadn't served a day yet.
我同意了移交
I approved that handoff.
我遵循了协议
I followed protocol in doing so,
其他人也是
and so did everyone else involved.
所以 我们谈完了吗
So... are we done talking about this already?
-这个案子现在是我们的了 -至少
This case is ours now.At the very least,
警长办公室会想要联合调查
the sheriff's office will want to do a joint investigation,
我觉得他们不会不战而降的
and I don't see them walking away without a fight.
可能不会
Maybe not.
但是你比他们厉害
But you're the bigger dog.
[door opens, closes]
嘿 你看到Kasie给了Vance什么吗
Hey, did you see what Kasie gave Vance
就那个 随机日礼物
for, uh, for that Random Day thing?
-一支笔 -哈
A pen.Huh.
谁会送人笔啊
Who gives a pen as a gift?
你生气的点在哪儿
What are you so angry about?
因为我从来没说过我想要个空罐子
Because I never said I wanted an empty jar.
别的人都得到了他们想要的东西
Everybody else got something they wanted,
主任和我却被嘲弄了
and the director and I got the shaft.
我是说 为什么 为什么Kasie要这么玩儿我俩呢
I mean, why would... why would Kasie play us like that, man?
KM-216
[gasps] KM-216.
在这儿呢
Here it is.
[grunts]
但是看看这些日期 一直能追溯到
But look at all these dates. They go all the way
2013年 那可是在警察把这个案子定为自杀之后很多年了
up to 2013-- that's years after the police ruled this a suicide.
Morgan Burke的男朋友Ben Ramsey
"Ben Ramsey, boyfriend of Morgan Burke."
看看这些
Look at all these.
-他是嫌疑人 -嗯
He was a suspect.Yeah.
不管是谁在调查这个案子
Whoever was investigating this must have thought this was
一定认为这是谋杀 不是自杀
a murder, not a a suicide.
是谁在调查呢
Who was investigating?
我的天
Oh, my God.
什么
What?
你看窗子上的倒影
Look at the reflection in the window.
能看到是谁在拍照
You can see who's taking the picture.
是Ziva
BISHOP: That's Ziva.
Ziva David
Ziva David.
Ellie Ellie 等一下
Ellie. Ellie, wait.
这主意糟透了
This is a bad idea.
如果Ziva怀疑Morgan的男朋友谋杀了她
Look, if Ziva suspected Morgan's boyfriend of murdering her,
有可能是他绑架了她 我们得和他谈谈
it's possible he abducted her and we need to talk to him.
不 我是说 不告诉别人
No. I mean, not telling anyone.
你不觉得McGee会想知道
You don't think McGee would want to know
Ziva在调查这个案子吗 Gibbs呢
that Ziva kept investigating this thing? Gibbs?
好吧 不论是因为什么 Ziva想要
Okay, for whatever reason, Ziva wanted to keep
秘密调查 我会尊重这一点
her investigation a secret and I'm gonna honor that.
你在保护一个你从来没有见过的人
Look, you're protecting someone you haven't even met.
为了什么呢 Ellie
And for what, Ellie?
Ziva David已经死了
Ziva David is dead.
我希望她没有
And I wish she wasn't.
人们不愿意在我面前谈起她
Look... people are afraid to talk about her in front of me
因为他们觉得我永远也无法与她相提并论
because they think I'll never measure up.
但那不是最让我难受的部分
That's not even the part that gets me.
最让我难受的是 我觉得被骗了
What gets me is... I feel cheated.
就好像 我永远也无法从她那儿学到东西
Like there are things that I could've learned from her
学到在别人那里学不到的东西
that I couldn't get from anyone else.
这种感性的东西
Look, this touchy-feely stuff
很明显不是我的长项
is... obviously not my thing.
但是不告诉Gibbs
But not telling Gibbs,
是个坏主意
that's a bad idea.
如果你不同意 那你就待在这儿吧
If you don't agree with it, you can stay here.
听着 我33分钟以后就到截止时间了
Listen, I have a deadline in, uh, 33 minutes.
我可能会丢掉整个账户 所以
And I could lose this entire account, so, uh...
你们能不能晚点儿再来啊
is there any way you could come back later?
这是你 在Morgan Burke家门外
That's you, outside of the home of Morgan Burke,
就在她失踪之后的第三天
two days after she went missing.
你在那儿做什么
What were you doing there?
我去探望她妈妈
I was visiting her mother.
Ziva David拍的这些 是不是
Ziva David took these, didn't she?
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
因为她 她觉得
[exhales] Because she-she thought
对于Morgan车坠下悬崖这件事
there was some questionable things
还有很多疑点
about Morgan's car going off that cliff.
她觉得她是被谋杀的
She thought she was murdered.
她认为是你干的
She thought you did it.
我是说 她跟踪了我好几个月
I mean, she followed me for-for months.
就像什么忍者一样 但是呃
She must've been like some kind of ninja, but, uh,
最后她认为我是清白的
well, eventually, she cleared me.
-那你是怎么知道的 -她告诉我的
And how do you know that?She told me.
而且她跟我保证会找到
And she promised to find the person
对我的孩子的母亲做出这种事情的人
that did this to the mother of my child.
你是知道的 对吗 Morgan在遇害的时候
You know that, right? Morgan was pregnant...
已经怀孕了
when she was killed.
那孩子是我的
The baby was mine.
-Ben 听我说 -你知道吗 Morgan的妈妈
Ben, listen...You know, Morgan's mom...
我曾深夜开车带她到Ziva的办公室
I used to drop her off at Ziva's office late at night
好让她们谈一谈 你知道吗
so they could talk, you know?
她曾经把Ziva称作她的夜光
She used to call Ziva her nightlight.
当我发现Ziva死了的时候
And when I found out Ziva had died,
我想 那束光
I thought that that, uh... that light,
那束寻求正义的希望之光也熄灭了 但是现在
that hope for justice had gone out, too, but now...
等 等一下 Ben 你刚提到Ziva的办公室 你是说在海军罪案调查处吗
Hold-hold on. Ben, you mentioned Ziva's office. You mean NCIS?
不 是另 另 另一个办公室
No. The-the-the other office.
在利兰大街那间房子后面的
The one behind the house on Leland.
利兰大街和哪里
Leland and what?
呃 东14街吧 大概是
Uh, east of 14th, maybe?
呃 听着 Ben
Uh, look, Ben,
Morgan的案子已经有了一些进展
there have been some developments in Morgan's case.
Torres探员会跟你解释清楚的
Agent Torres will fill you in.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
安珀紧急通告
【注：当发生儿童绑架案时，通过商业广播或交通信号灯等向社会大众传播的一种警戒通知】
[over P.A.]: Amber Alert.
[announcement continues indistinctly]
等一下 等一下 呃 怎么
Hang on, hang on. Uh, what...?
-嘿 Conrad医生 发生什么 -是Lily
Hey, Dr. Conrad. What...?It's Lily.
我离开房间去拿她的检查表 然后她就失踪了
I stepped out to get her chart, and she was gone.
噢 不 Lily
Oh, no, Lily.
Lily
Lily.
Lily 你看到一个小女孩 Lily
Lily. Did you see a little gir-- Lily!
Lil
Lil...
Lily
Lily!
嗨
Hey.
嗨 给我一点时间 我找到她了
Hey, just give me a minute. I have her.
嗨 你好 Lily
Hey, there, Lily.
只是我而已
It's just me.
[door closing]
我能告诉你一个秘密吗
Can I tell you a secret?
好的
Okay.
很久以前
A long time ago,
我曾有个女儿
I had a baby girl.
她很完美
She was perfect,
跟你一样
just like you.
但我只抱了她一次
But I only got to hold her once.
但我感受到了她小小的指头
But I felt her little fingers,
把她的头抱在我胸前 我爱她
and her head on my chest, and I loved her.
我
I... [inhales]
我是那么的爱她
I loved her so much,
以至于我 我不得不把她送走
that I, I had to send her away.
我妈妈也爱我的
My mom loves me, too.
是的 她爱你
Yes, she does.
所以我觉得
That's why I was thinking
你可能也是被妈妈送走的 对吗
maybe she sent you away, too, is that right?
现在轮到我们帮助她了
And now it's our turn to help her.
我有一个爸爸
I have a dad.
他的名字是Ben
His name is Ben.
妈妈说他就跟超人一样
Mommy said he was like Superman.
所以他应该能救她
So maybe he can save her.
是的 有可能
Yeah, maybe.
呃 那么你怎么想呢 Lily
Uh, and what about you, though, Lily?
你觉得你能为你的妈妈勇敢起来吗
Think you can be brave for your mom?
跟我讲讲锁起门的那个男人
Tell me about the man who locked the door.
他叫Robert
[shuddered breathing] Robert.
你知道他姓什么吗
Do you know his last name?
那里还有另一个男人
There was another man, too.
叫Buddy
Buddy.
他更友善些
He was nicer.
Robert不在的时候他给我们送吃的
He brought us food when Robert was away.
但是Robert
[crying]: But Robert...
Robert伤害了妈妈
Robert hurt Mommy
我那时躲在水槽下
and I hid under the sink.
妈妈说
Mommy said...
当我出去的时候要把她带给警察
to give her to the police when I got out.
谢谢你
Thank you.
Lily 亲爱的 你是怎么逃出来的
Lily, honey, how did you get out?
不 不 我要妈妈
[crying]: No. No. I want Mommy.
噢 我明白 我懂的
Oh. I know, I know.
我知道你想要妈妈 亲爱的
I know you do, sweetheart.
过来
Come here.
哦 没事的 没事的
Oh, it's okay. It's okay.
报告进展情况 McGee 这些区域搜查的怎么样了
Update, McGee. Where are we with the grid?
我们的探员们已经搜查了Lily现身处
Well, our agents have searched every home with a basement
方圆五英里内每一个有地下室的房子
within a five-mile radius of where Lily was found.
目前为止 没有收获
So far, nothing.
我们至少要知道Lily是怎么逃出来的
Bottom line is we need to know how Lily escaped
这样才能知道去哪里找Morgan
in order to know where to look for Morgan.
Torres和Bishop在哪里
Where is Torres and Bishop?
还没收到他们的消息
Haven't heard from them.
Gibbs探员 我是从布林县来的Atwood侦探
Agent Gibbs, Detective Atwood from Breen County.
是的 我看到你在电视上的讲话了
Yeah, I saw you giving a speech on TV.
是这样的 Jones治安官一个小时之前
Listen, Sheriff Jones sent over a formal request
发起了一个正式的联合调查的请求
for a joint investigation an hour ago.
-我没看到 -请求发给了你们的主任
I didn't see it.It was sent to your director.
是的 我收到了 而且我将拒绝
Yeah. I got it and I'm denying it.
这是我正式的回应 白纸黑字
Here is my formal response... on paper.
谢谢你让我省了一个信使
Thank you for saving me the cost of a messenger.
听着 我们只是想调动所有可用的资源
Listen, we're just looking to pool every available resource.
我们和你们一样都想让Morgan回家
We want Morgan home same as you.
你也知道 老大 如果他真想帮忙
You know, boss, if he really wants to help,
他可以去查清楚Morgan车里的遗骸到底是谁的
he could find out whose remains those were in Morgan's car.
因为正如你所说 那很明显那不是她
'Cause they sure weren't hers, like you said.
没错 你们为什么不去办这事呢
Yeah. Why don't you do that?
还请把我们的问候带给治安官
And give our regards to the sheriff.
[scoffs]
我跟你说啊 这支新笔
Tell you what, this new pen
写起来让我觉得自己像个大人物
makes me write like a big dog. [chuckles]
所以我在这里切了第一个口 让我能够
So I made the initial incision here, enabling me
让我能够翻开表皮 啊不对 是这个织物
to peel back the epidermis-- w-well, the-the fabric,
呃 让我看到了里面是什么
uh, showing me what was inside.
-填充物 -一些毛发
Stuffing.Hairs.
毛发里包含两种不同的DNA
There were two distinct DNA profiles in there.
我正在系统里查它们
I'm running them both through the system now.
天哪 简直太聪明了
SLOANE: My God, that is brilliant.
Morgan把DNA缝进了布娃娃里 然后告诉女儿
Morgan sewed the DNA in the doll, and told her daughter
当她逃出之后把娃娃交给警察
to give it to the police when she escaped.
她可以说是把囚禁她的人的身份给我们了
She essentially handed us the identity of her captors.
如果 我们能有结果
If... we get a ding.
噢 我等的
Ooh, that is what
-就是这个 -那些毛发吗
I am talking about.The hairs?
是的 其中一个找到匹配了
KASIE: Yeah, I got a hit on one of them.
一个叫Robert Hill的
A Robert Hill.
Lily说囚禁她们的那两个人名叫Robert和Buddy
Lily said her captor's names were Robert and Buddy.
Robert是主谋
Robert being the primary.
呃 看起来他在2008年就因为袭击他人被逮捕过
Uh, it looks like he was arrested in 2008 for assault.
被判了缓刑 最后已知的地址
Got probation, last known address...
现在是个单排商业区
is now a strip mall.
但是看起来一个叫Bud Hill的男人
But it looks like a guy named Bud Hill
把他保释出了监狱 关系 兄弟
bailed him out of jail. Relation, brother.
-就是Buddy -得到了他在首都的一个地址
Buddy.Got an address for him in D.C.
嘿 Gibbs 我们有发现了
Hey, Gibbs. We got something.
好的
Yeah.
[door opens]
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
Kasie打给我的
Kasie called.
-她帮我赶上了进度 - Bishop在哪儿
She caught me up to speed.Where's Bishop?
我不知道
I don't know.
老大
McGEE: Boss.
是他吗
GIBBS: That him?
是的 Buddy Hill
McGEE: Yep. Buddy Hill.
这里没有地下室
There's no basement,
也没有Lily和Morgan曾经待在这里的迹象
and no evidence that Lily and Morgan were ever here.
Sloane说他的兄弟是主犯
Sloane said the brother was the primary.
-更坏的那个 -是的 Robert Hill
The badder one.Yeah, Robert Hill.
他把Morgan带到其他什么地方去了
He's got Morgan somewhere else.
我的邻居说你在街上游荡
My neighbor said you were wandering the streets.
是的 我不知道具体的地址
Oh, yeah. I didn't know the exact address.
好吧
Mm-hmm.
所以Ziva是从你这里租的这个地方的吗
So Ziva rented this place from you?
只租了那个办公室
Just the office.
她从2005年开始借的
She started back in 2005,
提前付款 帮我渡过了财政问题
paid for it in advance to help me financially.
这就是她待人处事的方法 不是吗
Because that was her way, wasn't it?
坚强的外表下有着一颗温暖的心
A warmth beneath the armor.
是的 之后你没有再租给别人吗
Mm. You never rented it out after that?
没有
Oh, no.
上一次Ziva付钱是四年前
The last time Ziva made a payment was four years ago
在她死前从以色列支付的
from Israel before her death.
所以 严格来说 明年之前这还是她的
So, technically, it's still hers through next year.
出于尊重 我没有碰过这里
Out of respect, I haven't touched it.
等一下
Wait.
把你的徽章再给我看一遍
Show me your badge again.
我让你一个人待着吧
I'll leave you to it.
♪
[dialing]
Bishop 你在哪儿
GIBBS [on phone]: Bishop, where are you?
Gibbs
Uh, Gibbs...
我要告诉你一些事
I have something to tell you.
黑暗一直持续了几周
McGEE: "For weeks, it was darkness.
我已经停止计算忍受过的煎熬
"I had stopped counting the horrors I endured.
然后那个怪兽掀起了我的面罩
"And then the monster lifted the hood.
光照了进来 我看到了我的朋友们
"The light spilled in, and I saw my friend.
我的心就像重新认识了他
"My heart saw him as if for the first time,
我知道离开他我就无法活下去
and I knew I could not live without him."
这是她在索马里被抓住的事情 对吗
That was from when she was captured in Somalia, right?
你们都不知道这个地方吗
So, you guys didn't know about this place?
Gibbs 她没有告诉过你吗
Gibbs, she didn't tell you?
没有
No.
你告诉DiNozzo了吗
Did you talk to DiNozzo?
我试过了 他爸说他在回巴黎的路上
I tried. Senior said he's on his way back to Paris.
我留言了
I left a message.
老大 这里没有任何机密材料
Listen, boss, there really isn't anything classified in these.
我不想再读这些东西了
I don't feel right about reading them anymore.Okay.
好的
那就停下来吧
So don't.
但是告诉我她在这里干什么
But tell me what she was doing here.
她在NCIS担任联络官之后
Well, she started renting this place
就租下了这个地方
right after she became a liaison at NCIS.
前几本都是用希伯来语写的
The first few books are in Hebrew.
之后换成了英语
She switched to English after that.
每本书都代表了一件
McGEE: Each one of these books represents a case
Ziva参与的案子
that Ziva was working on.
她写下她的感受
She wrote about what she was feeling.
受害者家属的悲伤如何刺痛了她
How the grief of a victim's family pained her.
一个杀手如何进入她的世界
How a killer made his way into her dreams.
那些她没法写进官方报告里的东西
Things she couldn't put in an official report.
那些私事
Personal things.
就像每个案子都深深影响了她 她必须要
It's like every case got into her head, and she had
想办法释放出来 所以她独自一人
to get it out somehow, and so she did...
待在这间房间里 把东西都写在纸上
on paper, alone in this room.
这是关于Morgan Burke案
And, uh, this is the one on the...
的那本书
Morgan Burke case.
哇哦
Whoa.
我喜欢这个女人
I like this woman.
你找到什么了 Torres
What do you got, Torres?
我查阅了Ziva留在
I went through the rest of the files
NCIS资料的余下部分
that Ziva had at NCIS.
一些20多岁的嫌疑人
20-some-odd suspects.
Ziva把他们的嫌疑都排除了
Ziva... cleared all of them.
等等 你知道在交接之后Ziva还在调查这件事吗
Wait, you knew that Ziva was investigating after the handoff?
回总部
Go back to headquarters.
回到案子上 走吧
Get back on the case. Go.
老大
Boss...
Tim
Tim.
我能行的
I got it.
我来处理她的东西
I will take care of her things.
Gibbs 关于Morgan Burke
Gibbs-- Morgan Burke--
很显然每个案子都对Ziva很重要
clearly, every case mattered to Ziva,
但即使在交接之后她还在
but she kept investigating this one
一直在调查这个 而且你也知道
even after it was handed off and you knew about it.
为什么这个案子那么重要
So why was this case so important?
下次你再擅自隐藏相关信息
The next time you withhold relevant information,
你就走人吧
you are gone.
-Gibbs -第10条规则
Gibbs... Rule ten.
回办公室去
Get back to the office.
把注意力集中在案子上
Keep your head in the game.
死亡总有办法
JIMMY: Death has a way
找到我们所有人 无论是好人 坏人
of finding us all-- the good ones, the bad ones,
还是邪恶之人
and even the enablers of evil.
就像你 Buddy兄弟
Like you, brother Buddy.
你的尸体能告诉我们Morgan可能在哪儿吗
Body tell us anything about where Morgan might be?
这个么
Well...
我恐怕
[sighs]: I'm afraid...
一个字也没说
not a word.
-嘿 Jimmy -什么事
Hey, Jimmy?Yeah?
我看了一些
I, uh, I scanned through
Ziva的日记 她多次提到
some of Ziva's journals, and she mentions
一个 地下室知己
a "basement confidant" quite a bit.
她叫他H先生 代表着
She called him Mr. H., which stood for...
-像牡蛎一样开心吗 -是的
Happy as an Oyster?Yes.
-但不应该是蛤蜊吗 -应该是的
【注：As happy as a clam指非常高兴和满足】
[chuckles]: But shouldn't it be "clam"? It should.
应该是蛤蜊
It should be "clam," yeah.[laughs]
这是你 对吗
It's about you, right?
我不知道
I had no idea
你们的关系如此紧密
you two were so close.
这一定和我一直待在地面以下有关
Eh, it must be something about being this far underground--
在这里可能会更有安全感
you know, people feel safe,
让他们能够对我吐露秘密
like they can really confide in me.Hey, uh...
嘿
所以 你会觉得我读这些文字
so, do you feel like it would be an invasion of privacy
侵犯了她的隐私吗
for me to read this?
我只是 我很想知道
I just... I really want to find out
这个案子为什么对她如此重要
why this case was so important to her.
这我可以直接告诉你
Well, I could tell you that.
她告诉过你吗
She told you?
是的 她说过
She did. Yeah.
这是她作为NCIS菜鸟的第一个
So, this was one of her first solo assignments
个人任务
as an NCIS probie.
她只是寻找一个
She was just following up on a recruit
没有报到的新兵
who failed to report.
但当她到达现场 警长办公室告诉Ziva
But when she got to the scene, the sheriff's office told Ziva
-这个案子是他们的 -嗯
that the case was theirs.Mm.
是她把这个案子交了出去
She was the one who handed over the case.
是的 当Gibbs发现的时候
Yeah. And when Gibbs found out...
他那时
[exhales]He was...
他真的骂了她一顿
well, he really laid into her.
他说 Morgan Burke宣了誓
He said: Morgan Burke took an oath.
她就是一名海军
She was Navy.
我们从来不会把自己人交给别人
And we never hand over one of our own.
那是一个错误
That was a mistake.
这是一个Ziva无法忘却的错误
And it was a mistake that Ziva never forgot.
所以她从未停止调查
So she never stopped investigating.
这也是我想起她最多的一点
That was the thing that I will remember most about her.
她一直都是那么
She-she was always just so...
这样说吧
Put it this way--
如果她看到你眼中的热情
she'd see that fire in your eyes...
她会让你去读那里面的每一个字
she would have told you to read every word.
[takes deep breath]
他的亲弟弟割了他的喉咙
GIBBS: His own brother cut his throat.
哇哦 你确定吗
Wow. Are we sure?
Kasie很确定
Kasie is.
凶器上全是Robert Hill的指纹
Robert Hill's fingerprints were all over the murder weapon.
所以他信任他的弟弟 甚至在他不在家的时候
So he trusts his brother to feed his captives
给俘虏送饭 他的弟弟就用啤酒杯干掉他
whenever he's out of town, and he repays said brother
作为回报
by taking him out with a beer stein.
家人优先
Family first.
Robert Hill是在清理纰漏
Robert Hill is tying up loose ends.
他知道Lily逃跑了
He knows Lily escaped.
他很可能正带着Morgan逃窜
Good chance he's on the run with Morgan.
也许更糟
Or worse.
-Gibbs -Leon
Gibbs.Leon.
-时间紧迫 -这个 呃
Clock's ticking.This, um,
特别探员David的户外办公室
outside office of Special Agent David's.
知道 我正在处理这件事 我拿到那些日志了
Yeah, I'm handling it. I have the journals.
等这件事结束 我会把剩余的都清理出来
I'll clear out the rest of it when this is over.
那只是个小房子 我知道
It's just a room, I know.
但这一定会牵出很多事情来
But it must be bringing up a lot.
很多什么事情
Lot of what?
当一个女儿像这样隐藏秘密的时候
When a daughter keeps a secret like that,
当父亲的就该自问发生了什么
father has to ask himself why.
她觉得我不会同意她这么做
She didn't think I would approve.
她是对的
She was right.
[door closes]
Lily
Lily?
你好啊
Hiya.
我带来一个人想让你们认识一下
I have someone I want you to meet.
嗨
Hey.
没事的
It's okay.
这是
This...
Ben is Ben.
[whispers]: is Ben.
他是你父亲
This is your dad.
你好
Hi.
没事的
It's okay.
嗨 Lily 我 见到你真的很激动
Hey, Lily. I've been... been so excited to meet you.
我想这是属于你的 对吧
I think this is yours, right?
妈妈说你手上有一个印记
Mommy said you had a mark on your hand
是心的形状
that was like a heart.
是的
Yeah.
她说你就像个超人
She said you were like Superman.
求求你 你得救救她
[crying]: Please... you have to save her.
哦
Oh...
嗨 Lily 嗨
Hey, Lily, hey.
听着
Listen.
唯一能让我
The only way
帮到你妈妈的办法 就是你要告诉我
I can help your mom is if you tell me
到底是怎么逃出来的
exactly how you got out.
好吗
[breath trembling] Okay?
Robert讨厌细菌
Robert hates germs.
一切都必须干干净净
Everything has to be clean.
所以妈妈烫伤我们 弄得像被虫子咬了一样
So Mommy burned us to look like bites.
她告诉他我们的床垫子里面有虫子
She told him our mattress had bugs in it.
[breath trembling]
然后她在床垫里面给我掏出一个空间让我藏在里面
And she made a spot for me to fit inside the mattress.
你的妈妈说服Robert
SLOANE: Did your mom convince Robert
把床垫带到基地外面
to take the mattress out of the basement
扔在那里 是吗
and get rid of it?
他把床垫带到到处都是垃圾的地方
He took it to the place with all the garbage.
额 垃圾场吗
Uh, the-the dump?
[breath trembling]
等我听到他的车开走以后才爬了出来
I crawled out after I heard his truck drive away.
然后我就一直跑 跑到跑不动为止
And then I ran until I was too tired.
哦 嗨 你做得非常棒
Oh, hey, you did so good.
-你是个好姑娘 -你做得很好 Lily
Good girl. You did good, Lily.
嗨 加把劲 伙计们
Hey, buck up, dudes.
床垫应该就在这周围的某个地方
The mattress ought to be around here somewhere.
哦 哦 认真的吗
Oh. Oh, seriously?
拜托 千万别告诉我刚刚弄到我裤子上的是什么
Please, don't even tell me what just leaked on my pants.
天哪 这地方最好没找错
Mama, this better be the right place.
哦 不会错的 这里是那个小区方圆十英里内
Oh, no, this is the only dump within ten miles
唯一一个垃圾处理厂 对吧 McGee
of that storage unit. Right, McGee?
嗨 McGee
Hey, McGee?
什么 哦 对 没错 抱歉
What? Oh, yeah, yeah. Sorry.
这几天 这几天真是太疯狂了
It's been a... it's been a crazy couple days.
额 嗨 Kasie
Uh, hey, Kasie?
啊
Hmm?
我什么地方得罪你了吗
Did I do something to you?
-什么 -就比如让你不爽
What? You know, like something
以至于你就想给我一个空罐子
that would make you want to give me
作为礼物那种
an empty jar as a gift?
什么
[laughs]: What?
不 我只是 我从没听你提过你想要什么东西
No. I just... I never heard you mention something you wanted,
所以我决定送你一个你需要的东西
so I decided to give you something you needed.
我为什么会需要一个空罐子
What am I gonna do with an empty jar?
我不知道 放一些你不想失去的东西吧
I don't know. Put something in it you don't want to lose.
我不知道 听着 每个人都需要一个空罐子
I don't know. Look, everybody needs an empty jar.They do?
是吗
我找到了
I found it.
一定就是它了
This has got to be it.
Lily就是藏在这里面
That's where Lily hid.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
嗨 等等 所以Morgan Burke
Hey. Wait, so, Morgan Burke,
她制定了计划 并执行了计划
she makes a plan, she executes it--
那个床垫 藏在娃娃里面的头发
the mattress, the hairs inside the doll.
我们得考虑 如果Robert Hill正带着她逃离
We got to think that if Robert Hill's on the move with her,
她一定也在留下线索
she's leaving more clues.
你想说什么
What are you telling me?
我向公众提供一个热线 让大家一有Morgan的消息就打过来
I made a tip line for the public to call in with info on Morgan.
好的
Okay.
是的 Gibbs
Yes, Gibbs,
我读过了
I read this.
但我学到了东西
But I learned something.
Ziva 她敞开胸怀
Ziva, she let everything in.
她允许这件事影响自己
She let it affect her.
这使得她更加努力 而且
And it made her work harder, but it also,
使得她看得更清楚
it made her see clearer.
我告诉过你要保持头脑清醒
I told you to keep your head in the game.
这里面的东西很重要 Gibbs
The stuff in here matters, Gibbs.
看 看这最后一页
Look. Look at this last page.
Morgan的母亲 她得了癌症
Morgan's mom, she had cancer.
在她去世前 她口授了一封信
Before she died, she dictated a letter,
Ziva把它记了下来
and Ziva wrote it down.
你看到这个了吗
Do you see this?
Ziva许诺要把这封信念给绑架Morgan的人听
Ziva promised to read this to the man who did this to Morgan.
这又如何与案件相关了
That's relevant how?
等我们抓到Robert Hill
When we get Robert Hill...
我要对他念这封信
I'm gonna read him this letter.
我要履行Ziva的承诺
I'm going to honor Ziva's promise.
规则十 念出来
Rule ten. Say it.
念出来
Say it.
永远不要把个人情绪掺进案子里
Never get personally involved on a case.
那又怎样
So what?
那又怎样 我跟Lily建立了感情
No, so what? I connect with Lily,
你就派我去出外勤
a-and you put me in the field.
我想兑现受害者母亲的
I want to fulfill the dying wish
最后的愿望 而你就给我一句规则十吗
of our victim's mother, and you say "Rule Ten"?
不 Ziva把自己的感情融入到了每一个案子中
No, Ziva was personally involved in every case.
-你别跟我提Ziva -那你呢
Don't you tell me about Ziva!Then what about you?
在她移交案子的时候你非常生气
You were furious when she handed off the case
因为你也把自己的感情融入到了每个案子
because you take every case personally, too,
即使只有半秒钟
even one you only had for half a second.[quietly]: Enough.
够了
不 规则十 就是一派胡言
No. Rule Ten-- it's B.S.
我每次看到那张桌子 你知道我看到了什么吗
Every time I look at that desk, you know what I see?
看到她不在这里
She is not there.
你无视规则十 你就会深陷其中
You ignore Rule Ten, you go too far,
然后你就会跟她一样死去
you end up dead just like her.
回家吧 这个案子跟你没关系了
Go home. You're off this case.
嗯 嗯
BISHOP: Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
当然
Uh, of course, yeah.
-她让我别挂 -嘿
She asked me to hang on.Hey.
Look, I know I said you could have
我说过你可以
your tip line transferred down here,
把电话线转到我这里来
but that was before I knew Gibbs sent you home.
但后来我知道了Gibbs要你回家
Yeah, but the woman on the phone might have the location
是啊 但是电话里的女人可能有Robert Hill叔叔的
of Robert Hill's uncle.
地址
Uh-huh. What do you think Gibbs is gonna do
Gibbs会怎么做
if he sees you down in my lab working,
要是他看到你在我的实验室里干活
as opposed to at home regretting your life choices?
而不是在家反思人生选择
[elevator bells dings][quietly]: And there he is now.
现在他来了
[quietly]: Kasie, I have to do this.
Kasie 我必须这么做
GIBBS: Update! Let's go!
汇报情况 快点开始
Yes.
是的
Torres. Uh, hiya, Gibbs.
Torres 嗨 Gibbs
Listen, I wanted to explain
听着 我想解释下
about that hunk of wood in your parking space.
在你停车位上那块木头的事
Yeah, the white oak. I loved it.
那块白色橡木 我很喜欢
Now give me something else.Yeah. Okay.
-告诉我点别的 -好
Um, well, Lily said
Lily说
that when she was inside this mattress,
她在这张床垫里时
Robert Hill dragged it out of his house to his truck.
Robert Hill把它从房子里拖到卡车上
On the side that scraped the ground, I found something.
在与地接触的那一面上 我发现了点东西
The address of where they're holding Morgan?
他们关押Morgan的地址吗
Man, how easy do you think this job is?
老兄 你觉得这工作是有多简单啊
No. I found bird poop.You ID the bird?
-我发现了鸟粪 -你查出鸟的身份了吗
You mean did I get the bird's name and Social Security number?
你是问我知不知道这只鸟的名字和和社保号吗
No. Seriously, you two?
说真的 没有 你们呢
I analyzed the excrement and confirmed that it came
我分析了鸟的粪便 确定了它来自
from a caique parrot, and according to the website,
一一只凯克鹦鹉
"Caiques of Fairfax County," two pet caiques
根据Caiques of Fairfax County这个网站上说的 两只凯克鹦鹉
were accidentally released and have since spawned.
被意外放走了 后来产了蛋
They are often spotted in this area of northeast Virginia.
它们经常停在西弗吉尼亚的这个地方
还是有很多房子
Still so many houses.
Got something from Detective Atwood.
从Atwood探长那里得到了点消息
Love letter from the sheriff?
治安官的情书吗
Oh, no. Actually, Atwood did exactly what we asked him to do.
哦不是 实际上Atwood做了我们要求的事
He reanalyzed a sample of the remains found in Morgan's car.
他重新分析了在Morgan汽车里发现的样本
结果他们发现了耐热混凝土的痕迹
Turns out they found traces of heat refractory concrete.
From a cremation chamber.
来自火葬室
Yeah, the remains were likely stolen.
剩余的东西很可能被偷走了
Atwood tracked down a crematorium where
Atwood查到了Robert Hill
十年前工作过的火葬场
Robert Hill worked ten years ago
under the alias "Randall Howe."
他用Randall Howe化名去工作的
Randall Howe.
Randall Howe
Got it.
明白了
One home address for
在鸟粪半径范围内
a Randall Howe within our bird-poop radius.
有一个Randall Howe的家庭住址
发过来
Send it.
Bishop, did you hear that? We got him!
Bishop 你听到了吗 我们找到他了
Bishop?
Bishop
开灯
GIBBS: Lights.
他们不在这儿
TORRES: They're not here.
Kasie
Kasie.
Gibbs Bishop不见了
KASIE: Gibbs, Bishop's gone.
她在哪里
Where is she?
Fisher先生
Mr. Fisher?
他们发现我们了
They found us.
我在车道上看到了你的汽车
I see your truck in the driveway.
到船上去
Get to the boat.
快走
Move!
我得和你谈谈你的侄子Robert Hill
I need to talk to you about your nephew, Robert Hill.
-救救我 -闭嘴
Help me!Shut up.
到船上去
Get in the boat![whimpering]
NCIS
NCIS!
-救救我 -闭嘴
Help... Shut up.
把枪放下
You put the gun down,
否则她就会死 听到了吗
or she's dead, you hear me?
放下
Put it down!
我不是和你闹着玩的 女士
Look, I ain't playing, lady!
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
放下了
Putting it down.
就这样 Robert
There it is, Robert.
放下了 行吗
Putting it down, okay?
现在轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
我要你放她走
I need you to let her go.
待在那里
[grunts] You stay there!
待着
You stay where you... Uh. Uh.
You stay...[grunting]
[Robert grunting, Morgan groans]
[panting]
我做了个梦 梦见我成了她
GIBBS: I had a dream that I was her.
我被捉住了 无法逃脱
I was trapped. I could not get out.
然而我相信最后
Yet I believed there would be a savior.
[chamber clicking]
会有人来救我的 我相信
To the very end, I believed.
但有时 救世主不会到来
But sometimes, a savior never comes.
站住
Stop!
NCIS
McGEE: NCIS!
放下武器
Drop the weapon!
[Robert gasps]
[both grunting]
嘿 嘿
GIBBS: Hey. Hey!
你完了
You're done.
[grunts]
Ellie
Ellie?!
[grunts, pants]
好了
Okay.
我醒时 我知道我不能忘记
GIBBS: When I awoke, I knew I must not forget
变成她是什么样
what it was to be her.
[rhythmic breathing]
[groans]
哦
Oh. [coughing]
好了
Okay.
There we go.
-嗨 -Lily吗
Hi. [panting]Lily?
Lily在哪里
Where's Lily?
她很安全 你也安全了
She's safe. You're safe.
-好吗 好吗 -哦
Okay? Okay.Oh.
所以我抗争 我反抗
GIBBS: So I fight, and I kick,
我尖叫 我感受
and I scream, and I feel...
妈咪
Mommy!
那样很好
GIBBS: ...and that is good.
-嘿 -嗯
Hey.Uh.
[frogs peeping]
让它进来很好
GIBBS: It is good to let it in.
能感受到很好
It is good to feel.
因为感受带给我力量
"Because feeling brings me power.
感受让我明白
"Feeling is what makes me realize
我等待的救世主
"that the savior I have been waiting for
就是我
is me."
这是在第一页上的
That was on page one.
关于这件案子Ziva写的第一件事
The first thing Ziva wrote about this case.
是的
Yeah.
[taps on table]
Robert Hill在回去的路上犯心脏病了
Robert Hill had a heart attack on the way back.
在Mercy Point医院 118号房间
He's at Mercy Point, Room 118.
做你该做的事去吧
Do what you have to do.
-Gibbs -我知道
Gibbs...I know.
我知道
I know.
[door opens]
[door closes]
规则十：永远不要把个人情绪掺进案子里
Robert Hill
BISHOP: Robert Hill.
嘿 Robert
Hey, Robert.
是你啊 你想要做什么
You. What do you want?
我有东西要读给你听
I have something to read to you, and you're gonna listen.
Morgan母亲的信
It's a letter from Morgan's mother.
我收到了
Yeah, I got it.
什么
What?
有人已经来了 把它读给我听了
Somebody already came here and read it to me.
[exhales loudly]
谁
Who?
[Robert laughs]
她告诉我她会常出现在我梦中
She told me she was gonna haunt my dreams.
[door creaks open]
[sighs]
♪
Eleanor Bishop，为了我家人安全，请保守我的秘密